<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.3.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.innovationswitch.com//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.innovationswitch.com//" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-02-23T12:03:20+00:00</updated><id>https://www.innovationswitch.com//</id><title type="html">Switch - Let’s Innovate Together</title><subtitle>Corporate Innovation made easy – use our unique, process driven approach and suite of tools. Solve real problems using Design Thinking &amp; Lean Startup methodologies.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Does your innovation team have the right skills?</title><link href="https://www.innovationswitch.com//2018/02/15/does-your-innovation-team-have-the-right-skills/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Does your innovation team have the right skills?" /><published>2018-02-15T17:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-15T17:55:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.innovationswitch.com//2018/02/15/does-your-innovation-team-have-the-right-skills</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.innovationswitch.com//2018/02/15/does-your-innovation-team-have-the-right-skills/">&lt;p&gt;So, you’ve been tasked with leading innovation in your company. Your job is to put together a team that will not only come up with new revenue-generating ideas but will also take these from concept to marketable solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This team will require clear goals, a nurturing environment, and a simple way to measure progress. But that alone won’t be enough. They’ll also have to be diverse, multi-disciplined, and multi-skilled. With that in mind, I’ve put together a brief list of the top skills I’ve learned are imperative to a successful innovation team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;t-shaped-personalities&quot;&gt;T-shaped personalities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innovation teams are usually industry agnostic and not experts in a specific field. They should however be multi-skilled and work together - through the process of ideation - to create suitable solutions for the issues they’re tasked with addressing. The ideal personality type of an innovation team member is T-shaped. “What does this mean?”, you ask? Well, a T-shaped person is someone who shows a deep understanding and competency in specific and related skills - this is the vertical part of the T. In the horizontal part of the T, the person has an interest in (and the ability to collaborate with), people offering alternative skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-customers-keeper&quot;&gt;The customer’s keeper&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the innovation journey, it’s important that the end-user (or customer) be kept front of mind. The team’s intentions and thoughts should therefore be aligned with said customer. For this to echo throughout the innovation journey, we don’t expect to know what the customer thinks. Instead, we ask them, observe them, and delve deeper into the root cause of their perceived problem. Additionally, an innovation team should be testing their ideas with the customer to ensure a market fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shape-shifting&quot;&gt;Shape shifting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An innovation journey usually begins with a problem and an imagined (back-of-mind) solution. However, due to the iterative nature of innovation, your first thought will likely not be the resulting outcome. Solutions will always be optimised or even pivoted. In this ever-changing work environment, it’s incredibly important to be able to cope with shifting timelines, ideas, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tough-as-nails&quot;&gt;Tough as nails&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innovation teams address complex problems throughout multiple areas, and let’s face it, many personality types would not be able to handle this aspect of the job. So, persistence and resilience - not giving up when a topic is confusing or difficult - is the mark of any good innovation team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In keeping with the theme of persistence and resilience, it’s important to note that the iterative nature of innovation means that we don’t always get to the root of the problem on the first try. So, we would have to be dogged in asking questions to drive down beyond the symptom. From an organisational perspective, buy-in at every level is crucial. Here persistence and resilience become a critical skill in driving and implementing organisational change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;eternal-dreamers&quot;&gt;Eternal dreamers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team members should dream big to ensure their own self-doubt doesn’t sway their decisions. They should be thinking on the edge of impossible, of normal even. Putting constraints on aspirations and dreams could seriously disadvantage the ideation process in the innovation journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several other skills and characteristics that make innovation teams great, and they can be found in anyone, not just people who consider themselves innovators. Innovation is a process. With guidance, the right people, and the right mindset, any company (large or small) can innovate. Need help putting your innovation team together? Contact me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:craig.eliasov@innovationswitch.com&quot;&gt;craig.eliasov@innovationswitch.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Craig Eliasov</name><email>craig@innovationswitch.com</email></author><category term="Innovation Best Practice" /><category term="Innovation Team" /><summary type="html">So, you’ve been tasked with leading innovation in your company. Your job is to put together a team that will not only come up with new revenue-generating ideas but will also take these from concept to marketable solutions. This team will require clear goals, a nurturing environment, and a simple way to measure progress. But that alone won’t be enough. They’ll also have to be diverse, multi-disciplined, and multi-skilled. With that in mind, I’ve put together a brief list of the top skills I’ve learned are imperative to a successful innovation team.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Are you building your house of ‘innovation culture’ on sand?</title><link href="https://www.innovationswitch.com//2018/02/08/are-you-building-your-house-of-innovation-culture-on-sand/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Are you building your house of ‘innovation culture’ on sand?" /><published>2018-02-08T10:47:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-08T10:47:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.innovationswitch.com//2018/02/08/are-you-building-your-house-of-innovation-culture-on-sand</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.innovationswitch.com//2018/02/08/are-you-building-your-house-of-innovation-culture-on-sand/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-emphasis-on-innovation&quot;&gt;The emphasis on Innovation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a saying that goes “you are the average of the five people you spend most of your time with”. Inevitably, you start picking up their habits (good and bad), motivations, and behaviour, and so, over time these people influence your personality. This is often the point that most organisations miss – they overlook organisational culture when trying to implement new strategies. With innovation being at the top of just about every organisation’s agenda, building a culture in which team members can exchange ideas, and then implement best (and fastest) processes to get to market-ready solutions, is more important than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Innovation is commonly misunderstood, as it is mostly associated with technology or an assortment of new solutions. The truth is all these things are the product of innovation being applied well. Applying innovation well requires a strong foundation. Imagine trying to build a house on a foundation of sand, it wouldn’t be able to withstand any types of storms that are thrown at it. The same goes for driving a culture of innovation. All efforts will be in vain unless one has a solid foundation, because the proverbial storms are inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what exactly is the key to building a culture of innovation in your organisation? Well, the important thing to remember is that it won’t be a single action. It’s fundamentally a combination of things that include &lt;strong&gt;leadership&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;structure&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;talent&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;leadership-in-tune-with-the-companys-dna&quot;&gt;Leadership in tune with the company’s DNA&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who know the organisation well and understand how it works are key to strategically steering it. Their approach sets the norms and values for the broader team. Their role is not to monitor what people do and be ready to punish them for “wrong” actions – this inhibits innovation and often fosters a culture of fear. Instead, good leadership is about understanding the organisational landscape and assisting the team to navigate it. Innovation is not about buzzwords, or looking the part, it must be purposeful. It’s therefore critical that those in charge of driving innovation efforts understand the organisation’s problems and challenges, politics, and its people. Good leadership is being in-tune with the company’s DNA and gradually working on changing it for the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;structures-that-breed-versatility-and-birth-innovation&quot;&gt;Structures that breed versatility and birth innovation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many organisations claim to have a flat structure, but what exactly does this mean? A flat structure implies that everyone within the organisation or area can interact and collaborate irrespective of title. In fact, titles don’t exist. Rather, it’s their roles that matter, and these continuously change according to the nature of the work being done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, as we’ve said, innovation is about more than just the creation of solutions, it’s a way of work. The way in which a team is structured ultimately determines overall morale and the quality of their delivery. There is no perfect recipe for how to achieve this but what’s important is that everyone creates and adopts a set of key principles. Examples of these could be that meetings not be longer than the agreed time, or even the introduction of 15-minute stand-ups for quick (and punchy) project sessions. Don’t feel too discouraged at the beginning because flat structures at times feel disjointed and messy. The key is to keep at it and iterate on it. It’ll take a while to undo years of conditioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flat structures are important in driving a culture of innovation because everybody has a say in how things get done, not just in theory, but in practice. This way of organising often unearths talent that previously went unnoticed, as individuals are encouraged to contribute in various forms, depending on the task at hand. Freedom breeds versatility, and versatility births innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;talent-that-can-drive-change-and-raise-the-bar&quot;&gt;Talent that can drive change and raise the bar&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s key to understand the organisation’s desired state with regards to building a culture of innovation. This makes finding the right fit, simpler. Once you’ve found the right talent – knowledgeable, imaginative, persistent, and bold – it’s important to allow for the culture in which they work to emerge, with a set of principles that have been applied of course. It’s critical that this talent be nurtured, and for leaders to exercise patience, because innovation is a change journey. And with change comes resistance. Not everyone in the organisation will embrace your efforts because you’re disrupting the comfort zone. Be prepared for the individuals who will defend the status quo with everything they’ve got. They’ll perhaps be your biggest hurdle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By no means is the combination above exhaustive. There are several other things that are needed to drive a culture of innovation. The above will simply assist in establishing a solid foundation from which to start. Foundation is critical, it doesn’t matter how great the blueprint looks. Before you initiate or embark on an innovation journey ask yourself this: &lt;strong&gt;Am I building on sand or a solid foundation?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Thabo Ramphore</name><email>thabo.ramphore@innovationswitch.com</email></author><category term="Innovation Cuulture" /><category term="Innovation Best Practice" /><category term="Change Management" /><summary type="html">The emphasis on Innovation There’s a saying that goes “you are the average of the five people you spend most of your time with”. Inevitably, you start picking up their habits (good and bad), motivations, and behaviour, and so, over time these people influence your personality. This is often the point that most organisations miss – they overlook organisational culture when trying to implement new strategies. With innovation being at the top of just about every organisation’s agenda, building a culture in which team members can exchange ideas, and then implement best (and fastest) processes to get to market-ready solutions, is more important than ever. Innovation is commonly misunderstood, as it is mostly associated with technology or an assortment of new solutions. The truth is all these things are the product of innovation being applied well. Applying innovation well requires a strong foundation. Imagine trying to build a house on a foundation of sand, it wouldn’t be able to withstand any types of storms that are thrown at it. The same goes for driving a culture of innovation. All efforts will be in vain unless one has a solid foundation, because the proverbial storms are inevitable. But what exactly is the key to building a culture of innovation in your organisation? Well, the important thing to remember is that it won’t be a single action. It’s fundamentally a combination of things that include leadership, structure, and talent.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The recipe for innovation</title><link href="https://www.innovationswitch.com//2017/04/25/the-recipe-for-innovation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The recipe for innovation" /><published>2017-04-25T14:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-25T14:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.innovationswitch.com//2017/04/25/the-recipe-for-innovation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.innovationswitch.com//2017/04/25/the-recipe-for-innovation/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-emphasis-on-innovation&quot;&gt;The emphasis on Innovation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, big business places a large emphasis on innovation and it’s easy to understand why. Technology is changing the world that we live in at a rapid rate and one of the biggest consequences of this is that customers are expecting more from large, established organisations. People are comparing the experiences that they have when using, for example, Uber’s taxi service or AirBnB’s accommodation service, to the experiences that they have with their other product or service providers. The result is that customers now have less patience for anything that doesn’t address their needs or feels clunky. They are demanding more and if they don’t get it, they are likely to go looking for it somewhere else. Only the innovative organisations will survive.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-vectors-instrumental-for-innovation&quot;&gt;The vectors instrumental for Innovation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no doubt that innovation can mean very different things to different organisations but more and more it’s becoming accepted that there are certain pillars that organisations can put in place to foster and enable innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcodesign.com/user/katharine-schwab&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Katharine Schwab&lt;/a&gt;, writing for Fast Company’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://fastcodesign.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;fastcodesign.com&lt;/a&gt;, has reported that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ideo.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ideo&lt;/a&gt;, the world-famous design firm, has conducted a study of its own 26-year old archive of client projects (as well as some external resources on innovation) to establish how best to measure innovation in any organisation. In summary, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ideo.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ideo&lt;/a&gt; report that &lt;em&gt;“the most important element is the organisation’s ability to adapt and respond to change.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through its research, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ideo.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ideo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;“identified six basic vectors that it says are instrumental to an innovative, adaptive company”&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Purpose: &lt;em&gt;“A clear, inspiring reason for the company to exist — beyond just making money.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Experimentation: &lt;em&gt;“Trying out new ideas and making evidence-based decisions about how to move forward.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Collaboration: &lt;em&gt;“Working across business functions to approach opportunities and challenges from all angles.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Empowerment: &lt;em&gt;“Providing a clear path to create change in all corners of the company by reducing unnecessary constraints.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Looking out: &lt;em&gt;“Looking beyond the company’s walls to understand customers, technologies, and cultural shifts.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Refinement: &lt;em&gt;“Elegantly bridging vision and execution.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;scaling-the-principles-for-innovation-using-an-innovation-platform&quot;&gt;Scaling the principles for Innovation using an Innovation Platform&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These 6 vectors from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ideo.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ideo&lt;/a&gt; are a great top down summary of what it takes to enable innovation within large organisations. But how do you scale these principles for innovation throughout the organisation? How are these vectors elevated beyond just a paragraph in a mission statement? How do they become a part of an organisation’s DNA? The answer, in part, is through the use of an &lt;a href=&quot;/offerings/tools/&quot;&gt;Innovation Platform&lt;/a&gt; (but not one that only facilitates the crowdsourcing of ideas). Here’s why:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: One of the ways to be purpose driven is through the pursuit of a particular strategy. However, as with most theoretical documents, a carefully crafted strategy only has the desired effect if it infuses the organisation’s innovation efforts. Strategic drivers should filter and prioritise new products, services or business ideas. Ensuring strategic alignment is made easier if each innovation initiative is linked back to one or more elements of that strategy. An &lt;a href=&quot;/offerings/tools/&quot;&gt;Innovation Platform&lt;/a&gt; is always present, is scalable and can act as the gate keeper. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experimentation&lt;/strong&gt;: Large organisations struggle to identify the good ideas and fail the bad ones quickly. The most successful organisations are close to the customer and agile enough to repeatedly respond to customer needs. But how do you get closer to the customer? Design Thinking combines collaboration, user-centered design and creative thinking to match people’s needs with what is technologically feasible and financially viable. Lean Start-Up is a methodology for testing ideas and encourages you to constantly identify your biggest assumptions and to use creative ways to validate them. Ultimately, it is the combination of Design Thinking and Lean Start-Up that is helping organizations generate ideas, test them, and iterate their way to market success. Even though these methodologies are not altogether new, typically you’ll find that only a very small amount of any organisation’s employee base is practiced in the practical application of these disciplines (and these employees can’t always be involved in all of the new product or service work). An &lt;a href=&quot;/offerings/tools/&quot;&gt;Innovation Platform&lt;/a&gt; delivers Design Thinking and Lean Start-Up tutorials, step-by-step guides, templates, canvasses as well as tips and tricks to everyone’s desktop and can be leant on during every moment of the journey from Customer Discovery to Minimum Viable Product. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collaboration&lt;/strong&gt;: People with different responsibilities, skills, talents and backgrounds see things differently and when they collaborate a much deeper understanding of any opportunity is achieved. However, this desired level of collaboration is very difficult to achieve in large, siloed organisations. But what if all the organisation’s employees were registered and using the &lt;a href=&quot;/offerings/tools/&quot;&gt;Innovation Platform&lt;/a&gt;? Any employee pursuing an idea but requiring additional skills and experience on their team would be able to search for suitable colleagues to join and contribute the additional skills and know how required (they’ll even be able to see how that person has been rated on their contributions to previous initiatives).  &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Empowerment&lt;/strong&gt;: How often do initiatives lose momentum because senior management have meeting after meeting to do with business as usual. In addition to the ability to guide employees along a tried and tested framework for innovation, an &lt;a href=&quot;/offerings/tools/&quot;&gt;Innovation Platform&lt;/a&gt; provides a place for anyone to, at any time, virtually review prototypes, customer feedback and learnings and to provide their input, or to even recall why a specific idea was failed by a team at prototype phase. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking out&lt;/strong&gt;: Large organisations should be looking both internally and externally for solutions. For financial institutions, &lt;a href=&quot;http://matchi.biz&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Matchi.biz&lt;/a&gt; are a global fintech innovation match-making firm. &lt;a href=&quot;http://matchi.biz&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Matchi&lt;/a&gt; has worked with over 100 leading banks and insurance companies around the world, and has a database of over 2,500 FinTech companies with 700+ curated solutions. Their platform connects financial institutions with leading-edge financial services technology solutions and companies worldwide. Have a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://11fs.com/services/11fs-pulse/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;11:FS Pulse&lt;/a&gt; as well for &lt;em&gt;“immediate insight into your competition’s best digital banking experience”&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Refinement&lt;/strong&gt;: Ideas are cheap, Minimum Viable Products with early adopters and sustainable business models are rare. During the uncertainty of new product or service development, comfort can be found in an innovation framework and &lt;a href=&quot;/offerings/tools/&quot;&gt;Innovation Platform&lt;/a&gt; that has delivered products and services into the global market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps some of this has resonated with you, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Your%20thoughts&amp;amp;hashtags=InnovationPlatform&amp;amp;url=https://www.innovationswitch.com/2017/04/25/the-recipe-for-innovation/&amp;amp;via=SwitchInnvtn&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;let us know&lt;/a&gt; if it has!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Grant Ralph</name><email>grant.ralph@innovationswitch.com</email></author><category term="Agile" /><category term="Innovation Best Practice" /><category term="Technology &amp; Tools" /><summary type="html">The emphasis on Innovation Today, big business places a large emphasis on innovation and it’s easy to understand why. Technology is changing the world that we live in at a rapid rate and one of the biggest consequences of this is that customers are expecting more from large, established organisations. People are comparing the experiences that they have when using, for example, Uber’s taxi service or AirBnB’s accommodation service, to the experiences that they have with their other product or service providers. The result is that customers now have less patience for anything that doesn’t address their needs or feels clunky. They are demanding more and if they don’t get it, they are likely to go looking for it somewhere else. Only the innovative organisations will survive.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Combing Agile with Lean</title><link href="https://www.innovationswitch.com//2017/02/16/combing-agile-with-lean/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Combing Agile with Lean" /><published>2017-02-16T08:32:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-16T08:32:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.innovationswitch.com//2017/02/16/combing-agile-with-lean</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.innovationswitch.com//2017/02/16/combing-agile-with-lean/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;moving-beyond-agile&quot;&gt;Moving Beyond ‘Agile’&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agile product development has in recent times positioned itself as the number one and best way for innovation teams to successfully ship product to market. Let me be clear, I think that Agile is great as it focusses on frequent releases which is necessary in todays fast paced environment. The days of shipping code every six months in a waterfall approach and expecting to learn anything is rapidly becoming obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the risk with Agile, is that teams may be doing a good job of building the wrong stuff. Working within corporates my experience was that new features were often considered ‘DONE’ once the code was complete. The correct measure should be whether or not it has solved a specific customer problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;build-measure-learn&quot;&gt;Build, measure, learn&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why we encourage our clients to combine User Centered Design and Lean Startup principals. It eliminates the risk of building the wrong things. Following Eric Ries’s philosophy of &lt;a href=&quot;http://theleanstartup.com/principles&quot;&gt;‘Build, Measure, Learn’&lt;/a&gt; is how you get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/Build-Measure-Learn-ded6418f55c6a29d6fae74610436cce18df30d50a99c92329ca55754ede09eee.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Build-Measure-Learn&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integrating design, experimentation and user research into your Agile methods will help you understand what is likely to work and what customers don’t require. We encourage our clients to fall in love with the problem and not the solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;redefine-the-word-done&quot;&gt;Redefine the word ‘done’!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Did the latest release achieve the objective you set out to achieve?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Has the user’s behaviour changed the way you wanted it to?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early in the development of a new product, organisations must capture all hypotheses and notes about the predicted future. After each customer test or experiment it’s critical to conduct a post-mortem analysis:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What made us think that this would work?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What was the thinking around a particular feature?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What business goal did we intend to accomplish?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How did it measure up against our metrics of success?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fail-to-succeed&quot;&gt;Fail, to succeed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I encourage you to not see fast failure as wastage. You are not wasting if your process facilitates refinement and learning. On the contrary, fast failure, refinement and learning often lead to significant financial and time savings. If you are responsible for driving innovation, I encourage you to convert your executives into evangelists by continuously questioning them on the business goals and key strategic drivers. Walk them through the ‘Build, Measure, Learn’ processes and teach them to be hypothesis and benefit driven, not feature driven.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Matthew Adendorff</name><email>matthew.adendorff@innovationswitch.com</email></author><category term="Agile" /><category term="Innovation Best Practice" /><category term="User Centered Design" /><category term="Lean Startup" /><summary type="html">Moving Beyond ‘Agile’ Agile product development has in recent times positioned itself as the number one and best way for innovation teams to successfully ship product to market. Let me be clear, I think that Agile is great as it focusses on frequent releases which is necessary in todays fast paced environment. The days of shipping code every six months in a waterfall approach and expecting to learn anything is rapidly becoming obsolete.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Looking to increase user adoption? UX first!</title><link href="https://www.innovationswitch.com//2016/10/11/looking-to-increase-user-adoption-ux-first/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Looking to increase user adoption? UX first!" /><published>2016-10-11T07:45:34+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-11T07:45:34+00:00</updated><id>https://www.innovationswitch.com//2016/10/11/looking-to-increase-user-adoption-ux-first</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.innovationswitch.com//2016/10/11/looking-to-increase-user-adoption-ux-first/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-need-an-application&quot;&gt;We need an application!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you have decided that an application is the solution to your problem. First beware, your user may not want it. This applies to all types of applications (web, mobile, etc.). The key issue is gaining user interest. I’m not talking about the general desirability of your application. You would have already tested that by following &lt;a href=&quot;http://dschool.stanford.edu/dgift/&quot;&gt;Design Thinking methodology&lt;/a&gt;. However, that was a rough &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paper_prototyping&quot;&gt;paper prototype&lt;/a&gt;. So, what now? Make sure that your app user experience (UX) is flawless. An app that is easy and fun to use has fewer resistance factors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prototype-prototype-prototype&quot;&gt;Prototype! Prototype! Prototype!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hear you saying “I don’t have the time to build a pretty looking prototype right now!”. Well there is some good news. UX and user interface (UI) are different and complementary things. UX is all about the journey when using the app, while UI just changes how the app looks. Both of these toolsets are important, however, sometimes a UI designer and a UX designer have very different opinions. More good news though, it does not matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“What do you mean? Who’s opinion counts?”&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; This is a simple one - the &lt;strong&gt;customer&lt;/strong&gt; and only the &lt;strong&gt;customer&lt;/strong&gt; matters!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the solution is simple: choose the best method to create a prototype for UX testing with customers. Just a few of the options are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meteor.com/&quot;&gt;Meteor&lt;/a&gt; (for higher fidelity prototypes) - requires some extensive coding background&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.axure.com/&quot;&gt;Axure&lt;/a&gt; - requires some training but can build very good prototypes that can be easily deployed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.invisionapp.com/&quot;&gt;InVision&lt;/a&gt; - for building click-through demos, quickly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a short list of possibilities but with all the tech around today the choices are almost endless. Using something like InVision, you can create pen and paper drawings, take some pictures or scans and create a click-through. With a slightly better looking prototype, customers will get even more excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ux-testing-time-but-how&quot;&gt;UX testing time! But how?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By now you have researched different tool options and found some interesting applications to use. You quickly put one together, now what? It’s time to test! UX testing may well be different to your accustomed customer testing. First, have your goals clear. Make sure you have defined all the tasks that you want the user to complete. Throughout the testing process keep the user talking, they should be explaining what they are seeing and what they intuitively want to do. In the testing session, you should ideally have 3 people:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Facilitator - this person explains the purpose of the testing and what they intend to achieve. They will also be telling the user about the following tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Observer - this person should be watching the expressions and body language of the user to detect their non-verbal emotions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Note-taker - this person should be taking notes of where the user is in the process and what they are seeing and doing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the testing sessions, the facilitator is the only person (other than the user) that does any talking! There should be no guiding the user in any way. They should be left to figure out the task and if they can’t after some time, they fail and move on.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recording the session (both audio and video, if possible) is a good idea for later review. Each task will be rated on a scale (that you have defined) to determine:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;whether the user passed or failed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how intuitive and easy it was to complete the task.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a user fails, it really means that your UX design has failed and needs to be iterated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;go-forth-and-develop&quot;&gt;Go forth and develop!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this stage you will have tested several iterations of your prototype and will be ready to build your application. This entire process has ensured that your users will be able to easily use your app when it is released. All this hard work means there will be much less resistance to adoption - your ultimate goal.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brett Terespolsky</name><email>brett.terespolsky@innovationswitch.com</email></author><category term="Technology &amp; Tools" /><category term="User testing" /><category term="User experience" /><category term="User interface" /><summary type="html">We need an application! So you have decided that an application is the solution to your problem. First beware, your user may not want it. This applies to all types of applications (web, mobile, etc.). The key issue is gaining user interest. I’m not talking about the general desirability of your application. You would have already tested that by following Design Thinking methodology. However, that was a rough paper prototype. So, what now? Make sure that your app user experience (UX) is flawless. An app that is easy and fun to use has fewer resistance factors.</summary></entry></feed>